<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ofx:section xmlns:ofx="http://www.openfuxml.org"
			xmlns:l="http://www.openfuxml.org/list"
			xmlns:text="http://www.openfuxml.org/text"
			xmlns:media="http://www.openfuxml.org/media"
			xmlns:layout="http://www.openfuxml.org/layout"
			id="section.admin.geojsf.datastructure">
	<ofx:title lang="en">Data Structure</ofx:title>
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
		The data structure to of the core elements to manage maps and layers is shown in
		Figure <ofx:reference target="figure.admin.geojsf.datastructure.er"/>.
	</ofx:paragraph>
	
	
	<media:image id="figure.admin.geojsf.datastructure.er">
	    <ofx:title>Data Structure for Managing Maps and Layers</ofx:title>
	    <layout:alignment horizontal="center"/>
	    <layout:width unit="cm">6</layout:width>
	    <media:media src="svg.geojsf/er/core.svg" dst="admin/gis/geojsf/er/core"/>
	</media:image>
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
		There are four entities used for the data structure. The Category is only used to categorize
		different layer into thematic areas.
                The concept of specifying what should be shown on the map is based on layers.
                A layer is the smallest unit that can be set to be shown or not shown.
                The GIS component is working with maps and further geospatial information coming from 
                servers offering their services via Web Mapping Service (WMS) and Web Feature Service (WFS), this is also
                reflected in the data model.
	</ofx:paragraph>
	
	<l:list id="section.admin.geojsf.datastructure.list">
	    <l:type description="true"/>
	
		<l:item name="Service" lang="en" version="1" id="section.admin.geojsf.datastructure.list.service">
	    	<ofx:paragraph>
				A Service characterizes a 
				Web Mapping Service (WMS) or Web Feature Service (WFS)
				service by it’s URL. A service can offer multiple layers.
			</ofx:paragraph>
	    </l:item>
	    
	    <l:item name="Layer" lang="en" version="1" id="section.admin.geojsf.datastructure.list.layer">
	    	<ofx:paragraph>
				Each service can provide different unique Layers identified by their code (e.g. roads, infrastructures).
				It can optionally be marked as a "temporal" layer. A temporal layer includes information for different moments in time,
				e.g. the clouds over europe for every five minutes.
			</ofx:paragraph>
	    </l:item>
            
            <l:item name="View" lang="en" version="1" id="section.admin.geojsf.datastructure.list.view">
	    	<ofx:paragraph>
				The View is the binding between the map and the layer.
				 This entity stores additional default properties like the order number,
				 the default visibility or default legend information.
			</ofx:paragraph>
	    </l:item>
	    
	    <l:item name="Map" lang="en" version="1" id="section.admin.geojsf.datastructure.list.map">
	    	<ofx:paragraph>
				A map, or better a thematic map, is a composition of layers in a defined order.
				As stated above, layers are data-wise encapsulated in View entities, that hold
				information about their visibility, their ordering number (e.g. roads are shown on top of terrain)
				and the legend for this layer.
				The Views, along with a ViewPort (including information about the center of the map, its boundaries and the resolution),
				are all the information needed to display a map.
			</ofx:paragraph>
	    </l:item>
		<l:item name="Carte" lang="fr" version="1" id="section.admin.geojsf.datastructure.list.map">
	    	<ofx:paragraph>
				A service
			</ofx:paragraph>
	    </l:item>
	    
	</l:list>
	   
</ofx:section>