<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ofx:section xmlns:ofx="http://www.openfuxml.org"
			xmlns:l="http://www.openfuxml.org/list"
			xmlns:text="http://www.openfuxml.org/text"
			id="section.admin.installation.geoserver">
	<ofx:title lang="en">GeoServer</ofx:title>
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
		GeoServer is an open-source server written in Java and allows users to
		share, process and edit geospatial data.
	</ofx:paragraph>
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
		Designed for interoperability, it publishes data from any major spatial data
		source using open standards. GeoServer has evolved to become an easy method for
		connecting existing information to Virtual Globes such as Google Earth and NAS
		 World Wind as well as to web-based maps such as OpenLayers, Google Maps and Bing Maps.
	</ofx:paragraph>
	
	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
		GeoServer functions as the reference implementation of the Open Geospatial Consortium
		Web Feature Service (WFS) standard, and also implements the
		Web Map Service (WMS), Web Coverage Service (WCS)
		and Web Processing Service (WPS) specifications.
	</ofx:paragraph>
	   
	<ofx:section id="section.admin.installation.geoserver.installation">
		<ofx:title lang="en">Installation</ofx:title>
		
		<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
			Before installing <text:emphasis italic="true">GeoServer</text:emphasis> a user named 
			<text:emphasis italic="true">geoserver</text:emphasis> has to be created
			by the user <text:emphasis italic="true">root</text:emphasis>.
		</ofx:paragraph>
		
		<ofx:listing external="listing/admin/installation/geoserver/user.txt"/>
        <ofx:paragraph lang="en">
            The software product <text:emphasis italic="true">GeoServer</text:emphasis> is available at
            <text:emphasis style="typewriter">http://geoserver.org</text:emphasis> as a platform independent binary.
            The ZIP file needs to be downloaded and extracted
            in the directory <text:emphasis style="typewriter">/opt</text:emphasis>.
            The following command has to be executed by the user <text:emphasis italic="true">root</text:emphasis>
            in the directory where the ZIP file was downloaded.
        </ofx:paragraph>
        <ofx:listing external="listing/admin/installation/geoserver/extract.txt"/>
		<ofx:paragraph>
			After finishing your installation, you should do a test run with the current geoserver installation.
            First, be sure JBoss server is not running yet to avoid interferences. How to fix this permanently will be covered in the configuration section.
			Then change from the user <text:emphasis style="typewriter">"root" to "geoserver"</text:emphasis>, it is necessary to deploy the server with this user,
			otherwise the rights are changed back to root. Now go to the <text:emphasis style="typewriter">geoserverx.x.x/bin</text:emphasis>
			folder of the current geoserver installation and run the <text:emphasis style="typewriter">./start.sh</text:emphasis>. 
			The current geoserver installation should now start.

            It may be possible that geoserver gives you an error like this:
            <text:emphasis style="typewriter">JAVA_HOME is not defined correctly.</text:emphasis>
            In this case use the following command to set the JAVA_HOME system-variable in
            <text:emphasis italic="true">/etc/profile</text:emphasis>

            <ofx:listing>
                <ofx:raw>export JAVA_HOME=$(readlink -f /usr/bin/javac | sed "s:/bin/javac::")</ofx:raw>
            </ofx:listing>
        </ofx:paragraph>

	</ofx:section>
	
	<ofx:section id="section.admin.installation.geoserver.configuration">
		<ofx:title lang="en">Configuration</ofx:title>
		
		<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
			To avoid conflicts with the JBoss server, the port of the GeoServers web interface needs to be changed to 8088. This can be done by editing the following line in the
			<text:emphasis italic="true">start.ini</text:emphasis> file of your GeoServer installation:
		</ofx:paragraph>
		
		<ofx:listing>
				<ofx:raw>jetty.port=8088</ofx:raw>
		</ofx:listing>
		
		<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
			There are several individual configurations required for GeoServer to properly show the maps
			required for this information system. These configurations include:
		</ofx:paragraph>
		
		<l:list>
		    <l:type ordering="unordered"/>
		    
		    <l:item>
		    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
					A new <text:emphasis bold="true">workspace</text:emphasis> has to be created where all settings are set.
				</ofx:paragraph>
		    </l:item>
		    
		    <l:item>
		    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
					The <text:emphasis bold="true">data stores</text:emphasis> have to be configured. The most important one is the connection to the
					PostGIS database.
				</ofx:paragraph>
		    </l:item>
		    
		    <l:item>
		    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
					The <text:emphasis bold="true">coverage store</text:emphasis> need to be added for each raster data source.
				</ofx:paragraph>
		    </l:item>
		    
		    <l:item>
		    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
					The <text:emphasis bold="true">feature types</text:emphasis> are individual tables of the data store and provide access to vector data.
				</ofx:paragraph>
		    </l:item>
		    
		   	<l:item>
		    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
					All <text:emphasis bold="true">layers</text:emphasis> have to be configured, either with a coverage stroe or a feature type.
				</ofx:paragraph>
		    </l:item>
		    
		   	<l:item>
		    	<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
					For each layer a individual <text:emphasis bold="true">style</text:emphasis> has to be configured with a Styled Layer Descriptor (SLD).
				</ofx:paragraph>
		    </l:item>
		    
		</l:list>
		
		<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
			A manual configuration is possible, but takes a long time for all settings. Thus, a configuration tool is provided to automatically configure GeoServer
			with all required settings. The configuration tool connects to the REST interface of GeoServer. 
		</ofx:paragraph>
		<ofx:listing external="listing/admin/installation/geoserver/configuration.txt"/>
		
		<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
			The configuration tools needs a properties file with several entries, the path to the file has to be specified in the command line and needs to contain these
			entries: 
		</ofx:paragraph>
		<ofx:listing external="listing/admin/installation/geoserver/properties.txt"/>
		
	</ofx:section>
	
	
	<ofx:section id="section.admin.installation.geoserver.database">
		<ofx:title lang="en">Database Tuning</ofx:title>
		
		<ofx:paragraph lang="en">
			The geospatial tables are managed by the Application Server. To improve the performance of the system,
			some additional database indexes have to be created manually. 
		</ofx:paragraph>
		<ofx:listing external="listing/admin/installation/geoserver/database.txt"/>
	</ofx:section>
	
	<ofx:section>
			<ofx:title lang="en">Start GeoServer as a service</ofx:title>
			
			<ofx:paragraph lang="en" version="1">
				The next step is to configure the service with the shown script below. 
				Copy this script to your clipboard and past it into the VI terminal and save your configuration.
				Verify your installation with of the GeoServer by starting and stopping it
				(monitor this events with the log terminal).
				Use the commands "/etc/init.d/geoserver {start|stop|log}" to perform this test.
			</ofx:paragraph>
			
			<ofx:listing external="listing/admin/installation/geoserver/service/preparation.txt"/>
			
			<ofx:paragraph lang="en" version="1">
				To activate the service, the shell command
				<text:emphasis style="typewriter">update-rc.d geoserver defaults</text:emphasis>
				has to be executed.
			</ofx:paragraph>
			
			<ofx:listing external="listing/admin/installation/geoserver/service/etcInitD.txt"/>

			
		</ofx:section>
	   
</ofx:section>